<< 黑天鵝 >>
昨晚我做了一個瘋狂至極的夢
I had the craziest dream last night.
我扮演著「白天鵝」
I was dancing the White Swan.
編舞不太一樣，有點像莫斯科大劇院的版本
It was different choreography, though. It was more like the Bolshoi's.
那是序幕中的一場戲
It was the prologue,
魔法師羅斯巴種下了詛咒
when Rothbart casts his spell.
粉粉的，好漂亮…
Look how pink. So pretty...
真漂亮！
Pretty!
- 你今天心情不錯 - 他答應我，這一季讓我演大角色
- You're in a good mood. - He promised to feature me more this season.
早該如此
Well, he certainly should.
你在團裡熬了那麼久
You've been there long enough,
你是最努力的舞蹈演員
and you're the most dedicated dancer in the company.
起來
Up.
- 那是什麼？ - 怎麼啦？
- What's that? - What?
背後
There.
沒關係
Nothing.
你真不要我陪你去？
You're sure you don't want me to come with you?
乖女兒
You're a sweet girl.
你今天看見貝絲了嗎？
Did you see Beth today?
她居然還有臉回來
I can't believe she's back.
- 回來很正常啊 - 不會吧，她還沒看出來？
- Of course she's back. - What, she can't take a hint?
咱們團要破產了，她過氣了
The company is broke. No one comes to see her anymore.
如今，能堅持看完整場芭蕾的人沒有嘍
Oh, nobody actually comes to see ballet full stop.
才不是呢 皇家芭蕾舞團上一季不知道有多火爆！
That's not true. I heard The Royal had one of their best seasons yet.
他得換點新花樣，沒別的
He just needs to try something new. That's all.
不是換新花樣，得換新人
No, someone new.
- 換成誰？ - 老女人肯定不行
- Like who? - Like someone who's not approaching menopause.
真讓人難過
It's sad.
難過什麼？
What's sad?
貝絲多美啊！
Beth's such a beautiful dancer.
是啊，我奶奶也不醜
Yeah, so is my grandmother.
- 瑪格·芳廷一直跳到了50歲 - 是，我們知道 （瑪格·芳廷，英國人，20世紀最優秀的芭蕾舞演員之一）
- Well Fonteyn danced into her fifties. - Yeah, we know.
太好了
Great.
我他媽坐過了站
Thought I'd fucking missed my stop.
從79街一路狂奔過來
It's a hell-fit all the way from 79th.
跳得很好，尼娜
Beautiful as always, Nina.
放鬆
Relax.
一、二、三、四
And one, and two, and three, and four.
約翰，停一下
Stop, John. One second.
準備，各就各位
Okay, take position.
一、二、三、起
And one, and two, and three, and up.
一、二、三、四
And one, and two, and three, and four.
你好，親愛的
Hello, dear.
故事情節耳熟能詳
We all know the story.
純美無暇的纖纖處子
Virginal girl, pure and sweet,
被壞人變成了一隻天鵝
trapped in the body of a swan.
她渴望自由
She desires freedom
但只有真愛才能解除魔咒
that only true love can break the spell.
王子的到來，使她的願望幾乎成真
Her wish is nearly granted in the form of a Prince.
可就在，他要表白真愛之際
But before he can declare his love,
淫邪的黑天鵝，施展手段迷惑了他
The lustful twin, the Black Swan, tricks and seduces him.
白天鵝悲痛欲絕，跳崖自盡
Devastated, the White Swan leaps off a cliff,
在死亡裡…
killing herself. And in death...
她得到了解脫
finds freedom.
- 早上好，團員們 - 早上好
- Good morning, company. - Good morning.
這一季的開幕戲是「天鵝湖」
We will open our season with <i>Swan Lake</i>.
我知道，「天鵝湖」是部老戲
Done to death, I know.
但這部不同
But not like this.
我們重新改編，使愛更真，情更切
We strip it down, make it visceral and real.
這部新作品需要一個新的天鵝女王
A new production needs a new Swan Queen.
我要向世界展示一張全新的面孔
A fresh face to present to the world.
不過…你們有誰可以同時演繹兩個角色？
But... Which of you can embody both Swans?
白天鵝，和黑天鵝
The White, and the Black.
我剛才用手拍過的演員：
All the soloists I tapped:
下午照常綵排
Go to your scheduled rehearsals this afternoon.
而我沒拍過的女演員：
And the girls I didn't tap:
下午5點到主角排練室見我
Meet me in the principals' studio at 5:00.
謝謝各位
Thank you.
好了
All right.
- 繼續，剛才是左側練習嗎？ - 是的，老師
- Let's go. Did we do left side? - Yes, mistress.
該死！該死！
Fuck! Fuck!
看什麼？
What?
如果只是選白天鵝，你是不二人選
If I was only casting the White Swan, she'd be yours.
可現在不是
But I'm not.
音樂老師，奧黛兒之終篇，謝謝
Maestro, Odile's coda, please.
讓我看看你的黑天鵝，尼娜
Now show me your Black Swan, Nina.
放開，誘惑我們
Not so controlled. Seduce us.
不僅要誘惑王子 還有在場的人，觀眾，整個世界
Not just the Prince, but the court, the audience, the entire world.
加油，要像一隻結網的蜘蛛
Come on, like a spider spinning a web.
強一點！強一點！加油！
Attack it, attack it! Come on!
好的...
Well...
- 大駕光臨 - 對不起…
- Good of you to join us. - Sorry...
姑娘們，這位是莉莉
Girls, this is Lily.
她從舊金山來，填補麗貝卡的位子
Straight off the plane from San Francisco. She's filling Rebecca's old spot.
去熱熱身
- Hey. - Get warmed up.
不用，沒關係
No, it's okay.
不用熱身
I'm good.
需要我再來一次嗎？
Should I go again?
不用，謝謝你，尼娜，夠了
No, thanks, Nina. I've seen enough.
維羅妮卡，白天鵝變奏曲
Veronica, the White Swan variation.
快點，快點，快點
Come on, come on, come on, please.
好了，音樂老師
All right, Maestro.
二、三…
Two, three...
面試怎麼樣？
So how'd it go?
你回來晚了，我給辦公室的蘇茜打了電話
You were late, so I called Susie in the office.
面試！真不敢相信，他讓你面試主角
An audition! I can't believe he just sprang that on you.
怎麼樣？
So?
還好
It was fine.
還好？
Just fine?
小寶貝…
Oh, sweetheart...
別急，慢慢說
You tell me about it.
尼娜，沒事吧？
Nina, everything all right?
我沒事
I'm fine.
快好了
Almost done.
你練得太猛了
You're working yourself too hard.
- 我們都有不在狀態的時候 - 那個女孩，突然闖了進來
- We all have off days. - That girl, um, barged in.
我相信她不是有意的
I'm sure she didn't mean to.
你剛跳舞那會 如果我不領著你去教室，你一定迷路
For a starter, if I hadn't taken you to each of your classes, you'd have been completely lost.
明天我去找他，我要告訴他，我做到了
I'm going to talk to him tomorrow. I'm going to tell him I finished it.
沒必要撒謊
You don't need to lie.
他不會相信的
You won't convince him one way or the other.
寶貝
Oh, sweetheart.
我知道這讓你很沮喪
I know it's disappointing.
年紀一大，種種壓力…
When you start getting older, there's all this
如影隨形，我太瞭解啦
ridiculous pressure. God knows I understand.
不過，沒關係
But it's all right.
不管怎樣
No matter what.
你也許會再演貓那個角色
You'll probably get to dance the part of the cat again.
那個角色真不錯
That's such a wonderful part.
或者，他會讓你演大天鵝
Or maybe he'll make you a big swan.
不管怎樣，你都會光彩照人
Either way, you'll shine.
我知道
You know...
一覺醒來，一切會變得更美好
Everything will be better in the morning.
一定會的
It always is.
乖女兒
Sweet girl.
有事嗎？尼娜
Yes, Nina?
你現在有空嗎？
Do you have a minute?
- 我知道你很忙 - 不，時間正合適
- Now's not a good time. I get it. - Now is perfect.
那...
So...
我想告訴你
I just wanted to tell you that
昨晚，我又練了一次終篇
I practiced the coda last night and
我完成了
I finished.
我想讓你知道
I thought you should know.
尼娜，聽著，老實說 我關心的不是你的技巧
Okay, Nina, listen. Honestly, I don't care about your technique.
- 這一點你要明白 - 可昨天…
- You should know that by now. - Yeah, but yesterday...
別說了，還有…
No. Anyway...
我已經選了維羅妮卡，抱歉
I've already chosen Veronica. Sorry.
抱歉
Sorry.
明白了，謝謝你
Okay, thank you.
放棄了？
That's it?
不試一試說服我，讓我改變心意嗎？
You're not going to try and change my mind?
我也許真得會改變心意
You must have thought it was possible.
不然，幹嘛打扮的這麼漂亮到這來？
Otherwise, what are you doing here all dolled up?
我想要這個角色
I came to ask for the part.
好吧...
Well...
老實說…
The truth is...
我一直認為，你很適合白天鵝
When I look at you, all I see is the White Swan.
你美麗，怯懦，嬌柔
Yes, you're beautiful, fearful, fragile.
演白天鵝最合適
Ideal casting.
可黑天鵝怎麼辦？一人飾兩角，很難的
But the Black Swan? It's a hard fucking job to dance both.
黑天鵝我也能跳
I can dance the Black Swan, too.
真的嗎？
Really?
這四年來，你每一次跳黑天鵝…
In four years, every time you dance,
關心地總是每個動作的完美 但我卻從沒看見過你的激情
I see obsess getting each and every move perfectly right, but I never see you lose yourself.
從沒見過，為什麼會這樣？
Ever. All that discipline for what?
- 我想要完美 - 什麼？
- I just want to be perfect. - You what?
我想要完美
I want to be perfect.
完美不是控制出來
Perfection is not just about control.
是爆發出來的
It's also about letting go.
超越自我，征服自己，征服觀眾
Surprise yourself so you can surprise the audience. Transcendence.
能做到的人不多
And very few have it in them.
我認為我能做到
I think I do have it in me.
你咬我？
You bit me?
你居然咬我！
I can't believe you bit me!
對不起
I'm sorry.
老天，真他媽疼！
Man, that fucking hurt!
看什麼？
What?
她為什麼總盯著我？
Why's she always staring at me?
結果出來了
Hey, it's been posted.
Hey, it's up!
維羅妮卡
Veronica.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
嘿!
Hey!
為什麼胡說八道？
Why would you say that?
耍我嗎？
Your idea of some sick joke?
你說什麼？
What?
去死吧
Fuck you.
尼娜！
Hey, Nina!
恭喜！
Congratulations!
Congratulations.
你好漂亮
You're so beautiful.
恭喜！
Congratulations.
<i>喂？</i>
<i>- Hello?</i> - Hi.
<i>怎麼了，有麻煩？</i>
<i>What is it? What's wrong?</i>
我很好
I'm fine.
他選了我，媽媽
He picked me, Mom.
你能聽見嗎？
Do you hear me?
<i>- 跳天鵝湖？</i> - 我要跳天鵝女王啦！
<i>- For Swan Lake?</i> - I'm going to be Swan Queen!
媽媽！
Mom!
我一會就回來，想提前讓你知道
I'll be home soon. I just wanted to let you know.
<i>- 我愛你</i> - 我也愛你
<i>- I love you.</i> - I love you, too.
媽媽？
Mom?
媽媽，你在你房間嗎？
Mom, are you in your room?
尼娜？
Nina?
你在家嗎？
Are you home?
尼娜，我在廚房等你
Nina, when you get out I'm in the kitchen.
快來，寶貝
Come on, sweetie.
我的女兒，天鵝女王
My daughter, the Swan Queen.
我們的最愛，香草藍莓餡蛋糕
It's our favorite. Vanilla with strawberry filling.
媽媽，別切太大
Oh, Mom, not too big.
太多了…
Oh, that's way, way too much.
- 我們在慶祝，就吃這一次 - 媽媽…
- It's a celebration. It's just this once. - Mom...
我的胃不舒服
My stomach's still in knots.
好
Fine.
倒了！
Then it's garbage!
不要，媽媽，不要，對不起
No, Mom, don't. I'm sorry.
我太為你驕傲了
I'm just... I'm just so proud of you.
看起來真好吃
It looks so yummy.
好，好
Okay, okay.
謝謝，謝謝
Thank you. Thank you.
謝謝你，尼娜
Thank you, Nina.
非常好
That's very nice.
Very nice.
我知道白天鵝不成問題
But I knew the White Swan wouldn't be a problem.
你的任務是如何蛻變成邪惡的黑天鵝
The real work will your metamorphosis into her evil twin.
昨天我看見了她的影子
And I know I saw a flash of her yesterday.
再加一把勁
So get ready to give me more of that bite.
非常好
Excellent.
邪惡力量牽扯你，無法逃離，難以抵制
That evil force is pulling you that you can't escape. That's just out of your control.
你的感覺越來越清晰 「它在佔有我，佔有我」
So you sense it, you get aware of it more: "It's taking me, it's taking me."
多一絲絕望
A little bit more desperate.
對，你可以揮高一些，然後放下…
Right, and you can maybe go up a little bit and then come down, and then...
就是這樣
That's it.
瞧她的動作
Watch the way she moves.
不精準，卻很輕盈
Imprecise, but effortless.
真實無虛
She's not faking it.
非常漂亮！好，漂亮
Gorgeous! Okay, that's beautiful.
從頭再來一遍
Let's start again from the beginning.
從現在起，你和貝絲一個化妝間，小心點
You'll room with Beth from now on, so be considerate.
謝謝，蘇茜
Thanks, Susie.
這是盧萊先生送給你的
Those are for you, from Mr. Leroy.
真漂亮
They're beautiful.
我一會就來
I'll be back in a second.
失陪一會
Let me come back to you, please.
我們走
Let's go.
準備好讓這群狼品頭論足了嗎？
Ready to be thrown to the wolves?
我們需要錢，保持微笑
We need our cash, so please don't forget to smile.
女士們先生們，請靜一靜，好嗎？
Ladies and gentlemen, please, may I have your attention?
晚上好
Good evening.
我想宣佈一件非常重要的事
Let me make this very important announcement.
有一個人的表演曾讓各位目眩神迷 情難自禁
You all had had the chance and the privilege to be enchanted, transported,
有時甚至是悲痛欲絕
and even sometimes devastated, by the performances
她是真正的藝術家
of this true artist of our company.
也是我作品靈感的源泉
She's been a crucial inspiration to my work.
她是眾舞者的榜樣，更是…
A role model to all dancers, and even more than that,
舞台上最值得欣賞的一抹芳姿
a deeply appreciated presence on our stage.
你們都知道我說得是誰
You all know who I am talking about.
女士們先生們，貝絲·麥金泰爾
Ladies and gentlemen, Beth Macintyre.
不過，我們知道
But as we all know,
每個偉大的事業都有結束的一天
every great career has to come to an end.
貝絲將於本季末退出舞台
Beth is retiring at the end of season.
並在「悲劇女神」中作告別演出
She will be giving her farewell performance as Melpomene,
這也是我的第一支芭蕾舞劇
the role she originated in my first ballet.
我的小公主
My little princess,
我們向你致敬，將你深深懷念
we honor you. You will be greatly missed,
永記心間
and never forgotten.
不過，江山代有才人出
But as we bid <i>adieu</i> to one star, we welcome another.
這一季我們將推出新版「天鵝湖」
We're opening our season with my new version of <i>Swan Lake</i>.
領銜主演「天鵝女王」的 是這位楚楚動人的尼娜·塞耶斯
Taking the role of our new Swan Queen, the exquisite Nina Sayers.
不久，各位將一睹她的舞姿
You'll soon have the pleasure of seeing her perform,
不過現在，讓我們舉杯： 敬在場的各位，敬貝絲，敬尼娜
but right now, let's please raise a glass: To all of us. To Beth. To Nina.
敬永恆的美
To beauty.
馬上就好！
Just a second.
Just a second!
快點！我憋不住了！
Come on! I'm about to burst!
嗨，是你！
Hey, it's you!
我想我們還沒正式介紹過
I don't think we ever officially met.
- 我叫莉莉 - 嗨，我叫尼娜
- I'm Lily. - Hi, I'm Nina.
我知道，新的天鵝女王
Yes, our new Swan Queen.
- 幫我拿一下 - 好的
- Here, hold this. - Yeah, sure.
你一定興奮地要命
You must be so excited.
你緊張嗎？
Are you freaking out?
- 是的… - 是嗎？
- Yeah... - Yeah?
沒關係
Oh, it's okay.
換成是我，一定會暈頭轉向
Oh, I'd be losing my mind.
我得過去了…
I should get back...
別…別這樣，等一會
No, no, no, come on, stay.
陪我一會
Keep me company.
失陪
Excuse me.
你在這，跟我來
Oh, there you are. Come on.
他們恨不得把你吞了，你卻飄然在此
Hey. They tried to eat you alive, but here you are.
表現得很好
You did well.
真的？
- Really? - Mm-hmm.
你去哪？
Where are you going?
上西區
Upper west side.
順道去我家喝一杯
Stop at my place for a drink. It's on the way.
托馬斯，過去和凱倫·哈羅維打個招呼
Thomas, you need to say hello to Karen Holloway.
我得去拍個馬屁，一會就回來 在這等我，好嗎？
A minute more of ass-kissing. I'll be back. Wait for me here, all right?
你好，凱倫！
Hello, Karen!
貝絲！
Beth!
真遺憾，你要離開我們
I'm so sorry to hear you're leaving the company.
你是怎麼得到這個角色的？
What did you do to get this role?
他總說你缺乏激情
He always said you were such a frigid little girl.
你怎麼讓他改變了主意？
What did you do to make him change his mind?
和他上床？
Did you suck his cock?
不是每個人都需要這麼做
Not all of us have to.
你個無恥的婊子！
You fucking whore!
你就是個無恥的小婊子！
You're a fucking little whore!
冷靜，怎麼回事？
Whoa, what's going on here?
我得和你談談
Hey, I need to talk to you.
- 你喝醉了，回家吧 - 我得和你談談
- You're drunk. You should go home. - I need to talk to you.
不！你敢！你敢就這樣踢掉我！
No! Don't you do that! Don't you dismiss me like that!
我的小公主，拜託，冷靜一點
My little princess, please. Pull it together.
- 走吧 - 我會去找你的
- Come. - I'm coming by later.
我有件東西送給你，以表我的感激之情
I have something for you. It's a token of my appreciation.
- 好 - 別客氣，下手狠點，尼娜
- Right. - You make the most of it, Nina.
別介意，這行就是這樣
Don't worry. It's typical.
請坐，我們應該談談角色
Please. I thought it'd be good to talk about the role.
沖談一下拘謹的氣氛
Drown this a little.
我們不想彼此有隔閡
I don't want there to be any boundaries between us.
- 我也這麼想 - 很好
- No, me neither. - Good.
那麼…你有男朋友嗎？
So... You got a boyfriend?
沒有
No.
過去交的男朋友多嗎？
Have you had many in the past?
交過幾個
A few.
不過，都不是正式的
But no one serious.
你不會是處女吧？
You're not a virgin are you?
不是
No.
那就用不著害羞
So there's nothing to be embarrassed about.
你喜歡做愛嗎？
And you enjoy making love?
什麼？
Excuse me?
別大驚小怪，性
Come on, sex.
喜歡嗎？
Do you enjoy it?
我們必須談這個話題
We need to be able to talk about this.
我給你佈置一個家庭作業
I've got a little homework assignment for you.
回家後，自慰
Go home and touch yourself.
放鬆一下
Live a little.
天晚了，明天還有很多工作
Well it's late. Lots of work tomorrow.
門房會為你叫出租車
The doorman will find a cab for you.
聽起來今晚很精彩，真希望我也能去
Sounds like quite an evening. I wish I could have been there.
我向他們提過
You know I asked.
我知道，蘇茜對我說了
I know you did. Susie told me.
我猜他想和你單獨在一起
Guess he wanted you all to himself.
可是為什麼？
But why?
我不怪他
Don't blame him.
耳環哪來的？
Where'd you get these?
假的
They're fake.
我以為是真
Fooled me.
我自己能行
I can do it.
他一定整晚都在你身邊
He must have been by your side all night.
帶著你四處招搖
Showing you off.
- 尼娜… - 疹子而已
- Oh, Nina... - It's just a rash.
疹子？你在說什麼？
Rash? What are you talking about?
前幾天更嚴重，現在好多了
It was worse a few days ago. It's fine already.
- 你一定又用手抓了 - 沒有
- You've been scratching yourself again. - No I haven't.
媽媽！
Mom!
怎麼有這個壞毛病…
This disgusting habit...
老天，我以為你改了這個壞毛病，尼娜
Jesus Christ, I thought you were done with this, Nina.
披肩，從明天起披肩不許離身
Shrugs. You'll keep wearing the shrugs.
坐下，你有一件白色的
Sit down. You have the white one,
還有一件粉色的，應該能遮住
and the pink one. And that'll hide it.
然後，我再找一點那種貴粉底 我們還剩一些
And then I'll dig out that expensive coverup. We still have some.
不會有人發現的
No one will see it.
媽媽，別這樣
Mom, please,
因為這個角色，是嗎？壓力太大
It's the role, isn't it? It's all this pressure.
我就知道你承受不了，我就知道
I knew it'd be too much. I knew it.
你會沒事的
You're all right.
You'll be all right.
貝絲進醫院了
Beth's in the hospital.
發生了車禍
She had an accident.
不！
Oh no!
貝絲？
Beth?
怎麼回事？
What happened?
她衝進馬路被車撞了
She walked into the street and got hit by a car.
你知道嗎？
You know what?
我敢肯定，她是故意的
I'm almost sure she did it on purpose.
你怎麼知道？
How do you know?
因為貝絲做任何事都帶著一股黑暗的衝動
Because everything Beth does comes from within, from some dark impulse.
所以她的表演充滿著快感
I guess that's what makes her so thrilling to watch.
讓人戰慄
So dangerous.
某一時刻，甚至完美無缺
Even perfect at times.
但卻充滿著該死的毀滅性
But also so damned destructive.
是吵架那天發生的嗎？
Was it right after we saw her?
等等…這些跟你沒關係
Wait, wait, wait. This has nothing to do with you.
和你沒有關係，別擔心
It's not your problem, so don't let yourself be distracted.
現在你是主角，尼娜
This is your moment, Nina.
好好把握
Don't let it go.
你在幹什麼？
What are you doing?
尼娜？
Nina?
寶貝，我要來嘍？
Sweetie, are you ready for me?
加油！
And... Come on!
別控制，尼娜，我要看見激情
Forget about control, Nina. I want to see passion.
加油！
Come on.
伸臂
太僵硬了，沒有生氣，放鬆
Stiff like a dead corpse. Let it go.
放鬆，放鬆
Let it go. Let it go.
再一次
And again.
感覺你的橫隔膜
Feels like you have your diaphragm
有點收縮？
is in a bit of a contraction?
好
I'm okay.
將氣吸入我手的方向，吸氣
Breathe in to this hand. Breathe in to this hand.
深吸一口氣，好
Breathe in, all the way. Good.
呼氣
And exhale.
做挺背曲膝的時候，前面是不是有點僵硬？
Does it feel jammed in the front every time you <i>plie</i>?
有時會，不常發生
Sometimes, not always.
- 再拉一次，好嗎？ - 好
- One more pull, okay? - Okay.
- 好點嗎？ - 是的
- Is that okay? - Yeah.
大衛，能問你一個問題嗎？
David, can I ask you a question?
說實話，你會和那樣的女孩上床嗎？
Honestly, would you fuck that girl?
不會
No.
沒人會
No one would.
尼娜
Nina...
你的舞蹈缺乏激情
Your dancing is just as frigid...
該死！
Fuck!
我們還在工作，請把燈打開！
We're still working here, please. Lights!
開燈！
The lights!
謝謝！
Thank you!
各位，你們可以走了，謝謝
Okay, guys, you can go. Thanks for your patience.
不是你，你留下
No, no, you stay. You stay.
你們好好玩
Have fun, you two.
好
Okay
到這來
Come here.
過來，過來…
Come, come, come, come.
我來演王子
I'll be the Prince.
別控制，別控制
Let it go. Let it go.
感覺我的撫摸
Feel my touch.
迎合我
Respond to it.
快
Come on.
張開嘴，張開，張開
Open your mouth. Open it. Open up.
現在是我在引誘你
That was me seducing you,
應該你引誘我
when it needs to be the other way around.
等等…
Please...
誰在那？
Who is that?
嘿
Hey.
你沒事吧？
You okay?
你不能在這吸煙
You can't smoke in here.
你知我知…
Well, I won't tell if you won't.
所以...
So...
大日子越來越近，是不是？
The big day's getting closer and closer, huh?
我已經等不及了，相信你的表演會很精彩
Well, I can't wait. I think you're going to be amazing.
謝謝
Thanks.
那麼…
So...
你想談談嗎？
Do  you want to talk about it?
不知怎麼說
It's that hard to.
盧萊對你太凶是嗎？
Leroy playing a little too rough for you?
沒事的，尼娜，他是個混蛋
Come on, Nina. He's a prick.
他很了不起
He's brilliant.
沒錯，可他也很凶
Sure, but it's not like he's all warm and fuzzy.
你不瞭解他…
What you don't know is...
有人暗戀老師！
Someone's hot for teacher!
別激動，沒事，很正常
Oh, come on, it's okay. I don't blame you.
我要回家了
I should go home.
尼娜，別這樣，我開玩笑的
Nina, come on. I'm just playing around.
尼娜！
Nina!
寶貝？你在裡面幹什麼？
Sweetie? What are you doing in there?
再來
Again.
到底什麼問題？
Do you have any corrections?
莉莉告訴我，看見你在哭
Lily told me that she saw you crying.
心情很不好
That you were very upset
讓我對你溫和一點
and that I should take it easy on you.
不是我讓她說的
I didn't tell her that.
也許你該休息一下
Maybe you need a little break.
休息一、兩天，或者一個月，你覺得呢？
A day or two. Or maybe a month. What do you think?
她不該亂說話
She shouldn't have said anything.
不，是你不該發牢騷
No, you shouldn't be whining in the first place.
我沒有
I didn't.
你本該更優秀
You could be brilliant.
可你是個膽小鬼
But you're a coward.
對不起
Sorry.
別再說這句話！這就是你的問題
No, stop saying that! That's exactly what I'm talking about.
別再軟弱下去
Stop being so fucking weak.
再來！
Again!
莉莉…
Lily...
瞧瞧，是誰大架光臨了
Oh, look who's decided to grace us with her presence.
我要和你談談
I need to talk to you.
好
Okay.
馬上
Now.
閉嘴
Shut up.
來吧
Come on.
什麼事？
What's up?
你和托馬斯說了昨晚的事？
You told Thomas about last night?
是啊，早上我碰見他，他說你們遇到了問題
Oh, yeah. I ran into him in the morning and he said you guys were having some trouble.
他為什麼要和你說這些？
Why would he talk to you?
你說什麼，陛下
Oh, excuse me, your highness.
我告訴他你很努力，我相信你會很棒的
I just told him you're working your ass off and I think you'll be great.
你不該說
Well you shouldn't have.
好
Okay.
他對你毛手毛腳嗎？
Has he tried anything with you?
他可是惡名在外
He has a reputation.
我有理由擔心，尼娜，你每天回來的很晚
I have a right to be concerned, Nina. You've been staying late so many nights.
綵排，我希望他別佔你便宜，就擔心這事
Rehearsing. I just hope he isn't taking advantage, that's all.
他沒有
He's not.
很好
Good.
我不想你走我的老路
I just don't want you to make the same mistake I did.
謝謝
Thanks.
不是因為你
Not like that.
別像我一樣，毀了事業
I just mean as far as my career was concerned.
你什麼事業？
What career?
因為生你放棄的事業
The one I gave up to have you.
我28了
I'm twenty-eight.
接著說？
So?
僅僅…
Only that...
僅僅什麼？
Only what?
沒什麼
Nothing.
- 什麼？ - 沒什麼
- What? - Nothing.
你皮膚怎麼樣？
How is your skin?
很好
Fine.
還抓沒抓？
- Are you leaving it alone? - Mm-hmm.
讓我看看
Let me see.
- 脫掉襯衣 - 不
- Take off your shirt. - No.
有事嗎？
Can I help you?
是誰？
Who was that?
沒人
It was no one.
有誰？
Hello?
怎麼是你？
What are you doing here?
我是來道歉的
I just came by to apologize.
你說的對，我不該和他談你的事
You're right. I should have never spoken to him about you.
- 寶貝 - 等一會
- Sweetheart. - Give me a second.
- 吃晚飯… - 媽媽，拜託
- Your dinner... - Mom, please.
她可真難纏
Oh, she's a trip.
你怎麼知道我住哪？
How do you know where I live?
山人自有妙計
I have my ways.
老天，別緊張，辦公室的蘇茜告訴我的
Jesus, relax. I got it from Susie in the office.
這件事讓我很不舒服，我真的想彌補一下
Look, I feel really shitty about what I did, and I really want to make it up to you.
我請你出去吃飯怎麼樣？
So how about I take you out to dinner?
- 我不知道… - 好吧，沒關係
- I don't think... - Okay, that's fine.
喝一杯呢？
What about drinks?
寶貝，你該休息了
Sweetie, you need to rest.
- 老天 - 等等
- Jesus. - Wait.
你幹什麼？
What are you doing?
出去
I'm going out.
什麼？尼娜！
What? Nina!
你明天要上台
You're on the stage tomorrow.
他居然那麼叫她
I can't believe he calls her that.
- 真噁心 - 我倒覺得很貼心
- It's so gross. - I think it's sweet.
小公主？
Little Princess?
- 他可能對每個女孩都這麼叫 - 不可能
- He probably calls every girl that. - No way.
只對貝絲
That's just for Beth.
我打賭，過幾天他就會叫你小公主
Well, I bet he'll be calling you Little Princess any day now.
我不知道
I don't know about that.
他會的，上床的時候可別饒了他
Oh, sure he will. Just got to let him lick your pussy.
乾酪漢堡包，大份番茄醬
Cheeseburger, extra bloody.
非常感謝
Mmm, <i>dankesch霵</i>.
醬不夠可以叫我
Let me know if that's juicy enough for you.
我會的
Oh, I will.
乾酪夠嗎？
You have enough cheese?
你可多的很（意思是你很煩）
No, but you do.
慢用
Enjoy.
來
All right.
想打扮打扮嗎？
Wanna spruce up?
幹嘛，我帶著備用
What, I carry a spare
以防玩過頭
in case I wake up somewhere unexpected.
他怎麼樣？
So how is he?
托馬斯
Thomas.
我不知道
I wouldn't know.
- 少來 - 我真的不想談他
- Oh, come on. - I really don't want to talk about that.
好吧
Okay.
你真得放鬆放鬆
You really need to relax.
一顆給你
One for you,
一顆給我
one for me.
別擔心，貨很純，我保證 是從舊金山帶過來的
Oh, and don't worry. It's pure, I promise. I brought it with me straight from San Francisco.
這是什麼？
What is it?
開玩笑？
Are you kidding?
你從沒嗑過藥？
You've never rolled?
別擔心，它能幫你放鬆下來
Oh, relax. Here. It'll loosen you up.
你會看見無垠的夜空
Wait till you see the night sky.
藥力會持續多久？
How long does it last?
最多，幾個小時
A couple hours, tops.
不用了
It's okay.
好吧
Okay.
尼娜！
Nina, hi!
我們有伴了，這是湯姆，這是傑瑞
I thought we could use some company. So this is Tom and this is Jerry.
- 實際上，我叫安德魯 - 湯姆
- Actually it's Andrew. - Tom.
- 我得走了… - 不行，不能走，我剛點了酒
- I have to go... - Oh, no you can't go. I just got us some drinks.
我不應該…
I shouldn't...
我們明天要上台
We're on the stage tomorrow.
去哪？回家找媽媽？
So what are you going to do? Go home to Mommy?
來吧，玩一會
Come on, live a little.
藥力只有幾個小時，是嗎？
It's just a couple hours, right?
是的
Tops.
乾杯
Cheers.
你還沒告訴我你是誰
You haven't told me who you are.
我是個舞蹈演員
I'm a dancer.
不是這意思，你的名字
No, I mean your name.
- 尼娜 - 你倆是姐妹？
- Oh. Nina. - So are you two sisters?
- 是的 - 不是
- Yes. - No.
- 閨中姐妹 - 我們在同一個團跳舞
- Blood sisters. - We dance in the same company.
芭蕾舞女演員，難怪你們長的這麼像
Ah, ballerinas. No wonder you two look alike.
我也看出來了，你倆是同志小情人
I see now. Tom and Jerry here are gay lovers.
- 真幽默 - 我喜歡自娛自樂
- Very funny. - I like to amuse myself.
我從來沒接觸過芭蕾
I've never been to the ballet.
這麼看，你絕對不是同志
Then you are definitely not gay.
我是說，芭蕾有點枯燥，是不是？
I mean, it's kind of boring, isn't it?
- 老實說 - 不，不是這樣
- Be honest. - No it's not.
這麼說吧，不是每個人都能接受
You know what? It's just not for everyone.
找個時間過來看看，我給你們贈券
You should come sometime. I can comp you tickets whenever you want.
好，好
Yeah. Yeah.
- 那真是太棒了，謝謝 - 好了…
- Yeah, that would be neat. Thanks. - Okay well...
我們再喝一杯
I think it's time for another round.
乾杯
Bottoms up.
你們在排什麼戲？
So what are you guys working on now?
不好意思
Sorry.
天鵝湖
<i>Swan Lake</i>.
是嗎？
Yeah?
你看過？
You know it?
沒有
No, not really.
聽說過
Heard of it.
說的什麼？
What's it about?
是說一個女孩被人變成了天鵝
It's about a girl who gets turned into a swan,
她需要愛的力量打破詛咒
and she needs love to break the spell.
可她的王子卻愛上了不該愛的人
But her prince falls for the wrong girl,
於是她自殺了
and so she kills herself.
是個悲劇
It's not a happy ending then.
實際上，很美
It's beautiful, actually.
像你一樣
Like you.
什麼？
Huh?
我說你很美
I said you're beautiful.
很好笑？
That's funny?
某人的情緒上來嘍
Looks like someone might be rolling.
好了，過來，去跳舞
All right, come on. Come on, it's time to go dance.
尼娜！
Nina!
搞什麼？你去哪？
Hey, what the fuck? Where you going?
尼娜！
Nina!
你去哪？
Where are you going?
你知道現在幾點了嗎？
Do you have any idea what time it is?
很晚了？
Late?
你去了哪？
Where have you been?
到月亮上去了
To the moon and back.
- 你喝酒了 - 猜 對 啦！
- You've been drinking. - Ding ding ding ding ding!
還有什麼？
- What else? - Hmm?
你還做了什麼？
What else have you been doing?
原來你想知道他們的名字？
Oh, you want to know their names?
- 快去睡覺 - 是兩個人，湯姆和傑瑞
- You need to sleep this off. - There were two. Tom and Jerry.
- 閉嘴，尼娜 - 我和他們都上了床
- Be quiet, Nina. - And I fucked them both.
閉嘴！
Shut your mouth!
- 不許進來 - 你幹什麼？
- Don't come in here. - What's this?
懂不懂什麼叫隱私，我不再是小女孩了
It's called privacy. I'm not twelve anymore.
- 你現在腦子不清楚 - 走開！
- You're not my Nina right now... - Leave me alone!
小甜心
Sweat girl.
為什麼不叫醒我？
Why didn't you wake me up?
我要搬出去
I'm moving out.
是我的曲子！
My music!
托馬斯，真對不起
Thomas, I am so sorry.
繼續跳
Keep on going.
去熱身
Go get warmed up.
很好
That was good.
非常之好
Actually, really good.
好，休息十分鐘
Okay, let's take ten.
他只是讓我示範一下，明白嗎？
Look, he just wanted to mark it and asked me to step up, okay?
我睡過了頭
I overslept.
慘嘍，不過你玩很開心，對嗎？
Oops. But hey, at least you had a good time, right?
你在我酒裡下了東西
You put something in my drink.
沒錯
Yeah.
早上卻一個人先走了
And then you just took off in the morning.
早上？
In the morning?
你在我家過的夜
Yeah, you slept over.
沒有
Um, no.
除非你叫湯姆，還長了一根老二
Unless your name's Tom and you had a dick.
我們…
我們怎麼了，尼娜？
What, Nina?
是不是在夢裡和我上床了？
Did you have some sort of lesbian wet dream about me?
- 別說了 - 老天！
- Stop. - Oh my God!
老天，是真的！我成了你的性幻想對象！
Oh my God, you did! You fantasized about me!
- 閉嘴！ - 我床上功夫好嗎？
- Shut up! - Was I good?
最後一幕
The final act.
你的最後一場戲
You're trying to dance.
夢想幾乎成真！如此真實！
You've tasted your dream! Touched it!
可卻被砸得粉碎！
Only to have it crushed!
你的心破碎了！
Your heart is broken,
受傷了，你的生命在枯萎
wounded. Your life force fading.
鮮血滴滴下墜
The blood drips.
黑天鵝偷走了你的愛人 只有一條路可以熄滅痛苦
The Black Swan stole your love. There is only one way to end the pain.
你不再恐懼，接受了命運的安排
You are not fearful, but filled with acceptance.
你垂目看了看羅斯巴
And you look down at Rothbart,
又看了看王子
and then at the Prince,
之後，對，注視觀眾
and then, yes, at the audience.
然後，縱身躍下
And then you jump.
快點，跳，沒事的，跳！
Go ahead. Jump. Jump!
好了，大家去喝杯水，然後做分段練習
Okay, everybody get a drink of water, then it's notes.
你瘦了
You lost weight.
請脫下披肩
Take off your shrug, please.
很好
Very good.
向前看，快好了
Face front. We're almost done.
完成，好了
And that's it. Okay.
好了，非常感謝
We're done. Thank you very much.
喬治娜，我叫莉莉，托馬斯讓我來…
Georgina, I'm Lily. Thomas sent me...
我知道，給你也做一身天鵝女王的服裝
Yes, we have to get you measured for the Swan Queen costumes.
她怎麼在這？
What's she doing here?
他讓我做你的替補
He made me your alternate.
只是以防萬一
Look, it's just in case.
托馬斯，托馬斯
Thomas. Thomas.
- 托馬斯 - 什麼事？
- Thomas. - Yes?
不可以用她
It can't be her.
你先去，我一會來
Okay, why don't you just go. I'll catch up later.
怎麼了？
What's going on?
莉莉...你讓她做我的替補？
Lily... You made her my alternate?
這是慣例，莉莉是最佳人選
There's always an alternate. Lily is the best choice.
不，她想頂掉我
No, she wants my role.
每個人都想頂掉你
Every dancer in the world wants your role.
不，這不一樣，她別有用心
No, this is different. She is after me.
- 她想取代我 - 沒有人別有用心
- She is trying to replace me. - Nobody is after you.
不，請相信我…
- No, please believe me...
我知道你壓力很大 不過，你早上的表演很有突破
I know it's been a struggle. But you just had a breakthrough this morning.
明天是屬於你的，演一齣好戲，誰也不用想
Tomorrow is yours. Just give a great performance and you won't have to worry about Lily or anybody else.
現在回家，好好休息
Now go home and rest.
從「幻夢」再來一次
From the vision again.
怎麼回事？
What happened?
我有我的生活，別太拼了，明天是大日子
I've got a life.don't work too hard. It's a big day tomorrow.
我還在工作
I'm still working in here.
請把燈打開好嗎？
Could you please turn the lights back on?
有人嗎？
Hello?
你來幹什麼？
What are you doing here?
對不起
I'm so sorry.
現在我才瞭解那種感受，她想取代我
I know how it feels now. She's trying to replace me.
我該怎麼辦？
What do I do?
你偷我東西？
You stole my things?
我想完美，像你一樣
I was just trying to be perfect, like you.
完美？
Perfect?
我一點也不完美
I'm not perfect.
我什麼都不是
I'm nothing.
什麼都不是！
Nothing!
不是！不是！
Nothing, nothing!
乖女兒
Sweet girl.
媽媽？
Mommy?
乖女兒，乖女兒
Sweet girl. Sweet girl.
閉嘴！
Stop!
你在幹什麼？
What are you doing?
寶貝？
Sweetie?
尼娜？
Nina?
尼娜！
Nina!
走開！
Go away!
開門！
Open the door!
走開！
Go away!
開門！尼娜！
Open the door, Nina!
尼娜！
Nina!
出去！
Get out!
- 你到底怎麼了？ - 出去！
- What's wrong with you? - Get out!
- 出去！ - 你看見什麼了？
- Get out! - What do you see?
出去！
Get out!
沒事了
It's okay.
媽在這
I'm here.
你整晚都在抓
You were scratching all night.
我的鬧鐘呢？
Where's my clock?
- 別管了 - 幾點了？
- Don't worry about that. - What time is it?
- 今晚演出，我必須… - 不行，不行…
- The show is tonight, I have to... - No, no, no, no.
別擔心
Don't worry.
我給劇院打了電話，告訴他們你不舒服
I called the theater and I told them you aren't feeling well.
我一定得去！
I have to go!
- 不行，不行，不能去 - 放開我
- No. No, you don't. - Let go of me.
你身子不好，不能離開
You're staying in here until you feel better.
門把手呢？
Where is it?
這個角色會毀了你
This role is destroying you.
- 過去！過去！ - 尼娜…！
- Move. Move! - Nina...!
- 我的乖女兒到底怎麼了？ - 她死了！
- What happened to my sweet girl? - She's gone!
尼娜！尼娜！
Nina! Oh, Nina!
不，求你！
No, please!
- 你生病了！ - 放開我！
- You're not well! - Let go of me!
你承受不了
You can't handle this.
我承受不了？
I can't?
我是天鵝女王，而你只能一輩子跑龍套
I'm the Swan Queen. You're the one who never left the corps.
尼娜！
Nina!
你來幹什麼？
What are you doing here?
尼娜？
Nina?
她不是病了嗎？
She was supposed to be sick.
等等，我和她談一會
Give us a minute.
你還好嗎？
Are you okay?
我很好
I'm fine.
尼娜
Nina.
幹什麼？
What?
我已經讓莉莉上了
I've already asked Lily.
你正式宣佈了嗎？
Have you announced it?
經過貝絲那件事，你還想製造新話題嗎？
After Beth, do you really need another controversy?
我來了，托馬斯
I'm here, Thomas.
我來演
I'm doing it.
你的本性在障礙你
The only person standing in your way is you.
趕走它，釋放你自己
It's time to let it go. Lose yourself.
白天鵝，十分鐘後上場
White Swan, up in ten.
你在幹什麼？該你上台了
What are you doing? You need to be upstage.
你演得真差
You suck.
尼娜
Okay, Nina.
搞什麼？
What the fuck?
- 你沒事吧？ - 尼娜，你沒事吧？
- Are you okay? - Nina, are you okay?
你說，到底他媽怎麼回事？
Can you tell me what the fuck happened?
- 不是我的錯，是他失的手 - 真他媽失敗
- It wasn't my fault. He dropped me. - This is a fucking disaster.
開局不順吧？一定丟死人了
Rough start, huh? Must have been pretty humiliating.
滾出我的房間
Get out of my room.
我真為下一場捏一把汗
I'm worried about the next act.
我覺得你心有餘而力不足
I'm just not sure you're feeling up to it.
別說了，快別說了
Stop. Please stop.
黑天鵝還是讓我跳吧？
How about I dance the Black Swan for you?
走開！
Leave me alone!
該我了！
My turn!
It's my turn!
黑天鵝，五分鐘後上場
Black Swan, places in five.
快過來
Come on.
跳得漂亮，十五分鐘以後，最後一幕
Good job. Fifteen to the last act.
嘿，你真絕了
Hey. You were amazing.
說真的，我知道我們之間有點小誤會
Seriously, I know that things got a little messed up between us,
但是，老天，我服你了！
but I mean, holy shit, you completely blew me away!
好了，不說了
Okay, well I guess that's it.
不妨礙你了，再見
So I'll let you finish. Bye.
聽見觀眾的歡呼嗎？
Can you hear them?
他們愛你！他們愛你！
They love you!
我的小公主，我就知道你有那股魔力
My little princess, I always knew you had it in you.
來，我們一起出去
Come on. Let's take you out.
快去叫人！
Go get some help.
Go get some help!
你都幹了什麼？
What did you do?
- 我感覺到了 - 什麼？
- I felt it. - What?
完美
I felt perfect.
我完美了
I was perfect.
尼娜！尼娜！尼娜！
Nina! Nina! Nina!